上溯至宇宙初始  周遭还只是一片漆黑
In the beginning, there was darkness.
不知何时  忽地一声巨响
And then-- Bang!
时间空间以及物质皆由此发端
Giving birth to an endless expanding existence
此后不断膨胀  延伸  永无止境
of time, space, and matter.
每一天  新的发现都在不断为我们解开
Every day, new discoveries are unlocking
蕴藏于这里的那些神秘莫测
the mysterious, the mind-blowing,
令人大开眼界  致命的秘密
the deadly secrets of a place we call
我们称这个地方为"宇宙"
the universe.
在其40多亿年的存在时间里
Throughout its more than 4 billion years of existence,
地球经历了一些极其险恶的状况
planet Earth has endured some extremely rough days,
但是最险恶的是什么呢
but what were the very worst?
是和相距过近的行星发生碰撞吗
Was it a shadowing encounter with a planet that got too close?
不管当时有什么  肯定也都灰飞烟灭了
Had anything been there, it definitely wouldn't have survived.
还是炽热的致命射线
Or a hot shower of deadly rays
几乎把地球上的生命扫荡一空
that almost scoured the planet clean of life?
后续的热浪涌向四面八方
The blast from the impact would have laid waves
辐射范围达到数千公里
to thousand miles in every direction.
可以算得上是全球范围的声波
It's literally the sound waves around the world.
从摧毁一切的失控火山活动
From runaway volcanism that led to vast extinctions
到引发了全球深度冻结的微生物
to tiny microbes that triggered a global deep freeze.
生命在灭绝的边缘  摇摇欲坠
Life is teetered perilously close to the break,
一次又一次
time and time again.
此次生物灭绝数量之多  可能空前绝后
More life died then, than any time since and maybe any time before.
这是史上范围最广程度最惨烈的灭绝
This was the biggest and the baddest of them all.
最黑暗的时候已过去  还是潜伏在未来
Are the darkest hours behind us or lurking in the distant future?
做好准备  我们要倒数地球的七次灾难了
Take cover as we count down the seven worst days on planet Earth.
宇                   宙
地 球 的 灾 难 时 刻
本字幕由 YYeTs人人影视 原创翻译制作
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新 请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
■
翻译：阿拉蕾 Aqua 宝卡卡 Angelica 阳仔 Shinstar 时间轴：今
校对：傲骨    后期&总监：丢丢
■
也许你认为你经历过一些困难的时刻
You may think you've had some really rough days
比如严重的堵车
stuck in gridlock traffic,
上班途中人山人海
dodging the sea of humanity on their way to work
遭遇一场暴雨或暴风雪
or trapped in a torrential down pour or blizzard.
但是这些情况跟地球的七次灾难相比
But they can't even begin to compare
完全就是小巫见大巫
to the seven worst days on planet Earth.
纵观历史  地球遭遇过一些极其恶劣的情况
Throughout its history earth has experienced some really bad days,
灭绝生命的  创造生命的
days that have killed off life, created life,
以及重塑整个地球的
restructured the planet as a whole.
所有这些才形成了现今的地球
All of this together has formed the Earth that we live on today,
迈克尔・密史纳
美国宇航局  喷气推进实验所
但是那些时期
but during those really bad days
我们绝对不想去经历
we certainly wouldn't want to be here.
在我们看来
From our point of view,
地球确实经历过一些灾难时期
Earth has been through some pretty rough days.
灾难性的冲击极大地改变了地貌
Catastrophic impacts that have really changed the face of the planet
劳拉・丹莉
格里菲斯天文台
改变了植物群和动物群
and changed the makeup of the flora and fauna,
即地球上所有动植物
the animals and plants on the planet.
灾难时刻之一发生在地球的早期
One of Earth's worst days came early in its history
一颗飞来横星猛冲而来
when an uninvited guest barged into our neighborhood
在生命出现之际便将其扼杀在摇篮中
and threatened to destroy the planet before life had a chance to blossom.
忒伊亚星撞击
现在我们就来探索地球第七大灾难时刻
Let's dig in as the 7th worst day on Earth...
忒伊亚星撞击
The Theia impact.
大约在45亿年前
About 4.5 billion years ago
我们的太阳系是一片战场
our solar system was a battle zone.
巨砾相互碰撞  融合  形成行星
Giant boulders collided and coalesced to form planets.
早期的地球在灼烧形成之后不断遭到袭击
Infant Earth took hit after searing hit.
如果我们有时光机
If we could somehow magically transport ourselves
回到早期的地球时期
back in time to be in the time to be on the early Earth
我认为那会非常有意思
it'd be very interesting, I think,
能够亲眼看看那些大事件
to watch one of these large impact events.
地球表面
The surface of the Earth itself
炽热到接近熔点
was probably heated to a nearly molten state.
大气层布满灰尘
The atmosphere would be very dusty,
十分炎热
you'd be very hot.
那是一个我们完全陌生的环境
So, it would be a very alien world to us
丹・杜尔达
西南研究所
人类不可能生存
one that we couldn't actually survive on
不能像现在这样站在这里
just standing like we are here today.
石块不断撞击
Pounding by incoming rocks,
地球逐渐增至近似现在的体积
Earth slowly grew to nearly its present size.
有一个坚硬的地壳
Developing a solid crust,
厚实的地幔
a thick mantel,
铁质地核
an iron core
和炎热的大气层
and a hot stormy atmosphere.
有些人推测那时的生命非常脆弱
Some speculate that life may have taken a tenuous hold
但之后  就是灾难
but then disaster.
邻近一颗叫忒伊亚的行星
A neighboring planet named Theia
试图挤入地球的公转轨道
had been edging into Earth's orbital path.
此次入侵以最具灾难性的形式结束
The intrusion ended in the most disastrous way imaginable...
世界大碰撞
A collision of worlds.
这是一次十分惨烈的事件
It was a very violent event.
想象一下  火星质量的物体
Imagine something the mass of Mars,
即地球质量的一成
about 10% the mass of the Earth
唐・布朗李
华盛顿大学
从太空飞奔而来
whacking in from space
将自己撞得粉身碎骨
and blowing all its material.
那时地球表面的所有物体
Whatever was on the Earth at that time,
都因这次事件面目全非
it was radically changed by this event.
当火星那么大的行星撞击地球
When a Mars size object whacked in to the Earth,
亚历克斯・菲利彭科
加利福尼亚大学伯克利分校
这可是地球的灾难日
that was a bad day on Earth.
不管当时有什么  肯定也都灰飞烟灭了
Had anything been there, it definitely wouldn't have survived.
整个灾难历时数小时
It took hours for the full scope of the catastrophe to unfold.
随着两颗星球内核的融化
As the cores of the two planets melted,
地球的大气层物质被撞击飞向太空
Earth's atmosphere was blasted into space.
在超过一千摄氏度的高温下  地壳融化
Its crust liquified at over 2,000 degrees Fahrenheit,
地球和忒伊亚星地幔的大部分
and vast portions of both Earth's and Theia's mantels,
被抛射进入轨道
were rejected into orbit.
这跟电影里演的不一样
It's not at all like what you see in the movies.
你可以坐下喝上一杯咖啡
You could sit down and have a cup of coffee
发现还没撞完
and it's still going on!
大块物体撞击得花费很长时间
These, like you know, big objects take a long time to incur,
子弹打穿墙体那种火光可比不了这个
so these aren't the normal flashes you'd think about bullets hitting a wall.
这些喷射出的物质形成了一条巨大的轨道环
The bloom of ejected material created a vast orbital ring
之后逐渐融合为地球的新伙伴
before coalescing into a new companion for the Earth.
这就是新生的月球
The new born, Moon.
那颗成熟的星球和地球合为一体
That fully fledged planet merged with the Earth.
两颗星内部铁质内核融合
The iron cores would have come together,
含硅的地幔物质留在地球表面
and their silicon mantels were left on the Earth
并且形成了环绕地球的碟状带
and also it created into a disc that was orbiting the Earth.
这个碟状带的大部分物质撞击回地球
This disc most of it came back and crashed back on to the Earth
格雷格・劳克林
加利福尼亚大学  圣克鲁兹分校
但有一部分
but then a portion of it
重新组合  逐渐被越推越远
reformed and over time has been pushed out
最后形成了月球
and it's become the Moon.
足足过了1.5亿年  地球形态才稳定下来
It took about 150 million years for Earth to stabilize
融化的地壳逐渐冷却凝固
and its molten crust to reharden.
尽管忒伊亚星撞击对地球来说是灾难
But although the Theia impact was a very bad day on Earth,
但有助于地球形成适宜生命存在的条件
it was a very good day for its ability to sustain life.
月球形成后  地球的自转轴稳定了
When the Moon formed, it stabilized Earth's axis of rotation
否则来自其他星球的重力牵引
otherwise gravitational tugs from other planets
将导致地球混乱无序地变动
would have caused it to chaotically vary
而这样就会对严重破坏长期气候稳定
and that would have been bad for a long-term climate stability.
如果这种影响没有产生
Would we even have life as we know it
地球上能否有生命存在呢
if that impact had not taken place?
如果没有月亮  那么热带地区
Without a moon, you could really have a case with your tropics
彼得・沃德
华盛顿大学教授
在经过几百万年后  可能会转过来
within hundreds of thousands of years, could rotate
变成像两极地区
and become the Arctic or the Antarctic
这样所有生物就会死亡
and you kill everything.
当冲击结束后
With the impact over,
月球提供了轨道稳定性
and the Moon now providing orbital stability
地球的情况貌似安稳下来了
the stage seems set for a quiet future.
但事与愿违
But that was not to be.
行星形成  月球形成  皆大欢喜
You formed the planets, you formed the Moon, everyone's happy
但是突然间可怕的事情就发生了
and all of a sudden something terrible happens.
地球又一次的被卷入到一场浩劫中
Earth was suddenly caught in the cross fire once again.
第六大地球灾难时刻
Number six on our countdown of worst days...
太阳系后期重轰炸期
The Late Heavy Bombardment.
在忒伊亚撞击过去约一亿五千万年后
Approximately 150 million years after the Theia impact,
地壳冷却了
the Earth's crust cooled.
一些人推测  早期大洋甚至生命或已形成
Some speculate that early oceans and even life may have evolved.
但另一场大灾难将把这一切切摧毁殆尽
But another cataclysm would wipe the slate clean.
在太阳系的边缘
In the far reaches of the Solar System
外太阳系的巨大气体行星轨道开始波动
the orbit of the outer gas giants began to fluctuate
干扰了大量的彗星以及小行星
disrupting vast swarms of asteroids and comets.
数兆颗小行星脱离了原始轨道
Trillions broke loose from their orbits
并且朝着一颗布满岩石的行星冲来
and plunged inward towards the rocky planets,
开始了一段炙热的毁灭浩劫
launching an era of fiery destruction
也就是我们所知的后期重轰炸期
known as the late heavy bombardment.
我们知道有德州大小的陨石撞上地球
We know asteroids of the size of Texas hit the Earth.
任何该体积的陨石撞击都会导致大洋的消失
Any impact that big causes the entire ocean to go away.
地球一次又一次的变成不毛之地
We sterilize the Earth over and over and over
所以我们推断  地球上的生命不断进化
so the inference we have is that life evolved over and over and over
但是总是被这些陨石冲击所摧毁
just to be snuffed down again by these large impacts.
无休止的陨石轰炸形成了
The relentless bombardment gouged down craters
数千英里宽的环形山
thousands of miles wide
而这些陨石冲击持续了至少两亿年之久
and the hits just kept coming for at least 200 million years.
今日  历经数十亿年的侵蚀和板块运动
Today, billions of years of erosion and shifting plaque tectonics
当年那些陨石冲击的痕迹已经消失
have erased any trace of the cataclysm from the Earth's surface.
但在月球上的环形山就不一样了
But it is a different story on the crater face of the Moon.
我们可以很清楚的看到月球表面上的痕迹
We can see very clearly its record on the face of the Moon.
熔岩区就是在这次巨大冲击下形成的
The lava field basins were formed during the giant impact events
也就是在地球的后期重轰炸期
that occurred during the late heavy bombardment
所以我们便知在这期间有大型物体撞击地球
and so we know that large objects hit the Earth during this time.
但是这些天国的怒火
But this celestial reign of fire
或许还带来了希望之光[银光]
may have had a silver lining.
确实如此
Literally.
最新证据表明  在后期重轰炸期
New evidence suggests the late heavy bombardment
给地球表面带来的贵金属
delivered precious metals to the surface of Earth.
例如  银  金和铂
Things like silver, gold and platinum.
地球上原先的这些贵金属
Earth's original store these elements
随着地球慢慢变冷  已沉入地心铁核
had sunken in its molten iron core as the planet slowly cooled.
但是现在地球表面早已固化
But now with the planet already solidified,
这种贵金属仍贮藏在地表
this new supply of materials remain near the surface
未来人类可进行开采
able to be mined by future humans.
我们今天的科技极其依赖这些重金属
Today's technologies depend on a lot of the heavy elements that
是通过陨石/彗星撞击地球而得来的
were delivered to the Earth through impacts.
所以  这也许对地球上的生命是个灾难
So, it may have been very difficult for the life,
如果在重轰炸期有生命存在的话
if there were life on Earth during the heavy bombardment
但是这对地壳却是件好事
but it was very good for the Earth's crust
因为它们的冲击给地表带来了
to have all these materials that we now depend on
这些我们赖以生存的材料
delivered to the surface of Earth through impacts.
后期重轰炸期实乃对地球火的洗礼
The late heavy bombardment was Earth's true baptism by fire.
但是现在该轮到第五大地球灾难时刻了
But now as we reach number five on our countdown of our planet's worst days,
地球经历了有史以来最严寒的时期
Earth catches the worst cold in history.
一场极寒的气候危机
A climatic crisis so chilling
让地球上的生命差点冻结在进化历程上
that life itself was in danger of being frozen in its tracks.
忒伊亚大冲击和后期重轰炸期
Both the Theia impact and the late heavy bombardment
都让地球变成了一片火海
turned Earth into an inferno.
现在继续倒数  地球七大灾难时刻
But now as we continue our countdown of the 7 worst days on Earth
我们回到从前
we escape forward in time
到达不是炙热而是极寒的灾难时期
to a catastrophe not of fire, but of all encompassing ice.
第五大灾难时刻
Number five on our countdown.
"雪地球"
也就是被称为"雪地球"的冰冻灾难期
The frozen cataclysm known as Snowball Earth.
地球曾经历过一些灾难日
We had these bad days
但雪地球期可远远不止一天
and snowball Earth is much longer than a bad day.
它是长达数十万年的灾难
It's a bad hundreds of thousands of years.
雪地球期使整个行星变成了一个大雪地球
Snowball Earth is that the planet, it goes all snowball.
彼得・沃德
华盛顿大学教授
它让地球冷到整个大洋都冻住了
It cools enough that the oceans freeze,
大洋的冰层厚达三  六  十五米
down to 10 ft., 20, 50 ft. thick...
想象一下我们现在看到的北冰洋就知道了
Imagine the Arctic Sea ice we see now,
只不过当时整个地球都是如此
except the whole planet has that.
在一般的冰河期中  冰川会入侵温带
During a typical ice age, glaciers invade the temperate zones
最远至现在纽约和巴黎的位置
often reaching as far south as modern New York or Paris.
但在雪地球期  冰川仍锐势不减
But during Snowball Earth, the glaciers just kept coming
直到包围了整个地球
until they had encircled the entire planet
并且将海洋的冰层厚度扩大到1.6千米
and frozen the oceans to a depth above to a mile.
当时的平均气温已低至零下59摄氏度
As average temperatures plunged to a -75 degrees Fahrenheit,
赤道和今天的南极一样寒冷
the equator grew as cold then, as the South Pole is today.
而席卷全球的极寒  或许发生了两次
And this global deep freeze may have happened not once, but twice.
第一次发生在二十四亿年前
The first episode beginning 2.4 billion years ago.
在雪地球期间  整个地球的气候
During the Snowball Earth phase, the entire Earth has
都很像现在的南极地区气候
a climate quite similar to modern day Antarctica.
格雷格・劳克林
加利福尼亚大学  圣克鲁兹分校
极其寒冷  极其干燥
It's extremely cold, extremely dry,
狂风肆虐  荒芜一物
extremely windy, extremely inhospitable to life.
雪地球假设很好的解释了
The Snowball Earth hypothesis helps explain
曾是赤道的地区发现的冰川沉积物
the discovery of glacier deposits in areas that were once at the equator.
这一理论为  冰川从两极地区开始进发
It's theorized that as the glaciers marched on from the polar regions
它们把太阳光反射回宇宙
they reflected sunlight back into space
并且创造出一个强大的反馈回路
and created a powerful feedback loop,
无情地把地球气温一降再降
turning the thermostat relentlessly lower.
如果两极地区面积过大
If the polar regions get too large,
如果雪和高反射率的冰层到达低纬度
if the snow and high reflective ice coatings get to far down in latitude
它们就能把更多的太阳光反射回宇宙
they reflect more light back into space.
地球就会变得更冷
The Earth gets cooler.
冰层也就会更靠近赤道
The ice goes closer and closer and closer to the equator
这也就形成了恶性循环
so it's gotta be kind of a runaway process
至少它将会将地球完全冻结
as the least it will freeze over of the Earth.
但是究竟是什么引发了首次雪地球期呢
But what caused the first Snowball Earth?
科学家们认为罪魁祸首可能是生命本身
Scientists think the culprit actually may have been life itself.
地球生命诞生之初  大气中的主要气体
The gas that was most prevalent when life first appeared in the Earth
不是氧气  而是甲烷
wasn't oxygen, it was methane.
那时的生命  单细胞细菌
Creatures at that time, single-celled bacteria
会将甲烷作为日常生存代谢过程的一部分
would have used methane as part of their normal living processes.
甲烷是一种显著的温室气体
Methane is a phenomenal greenhouse gas.
迈克尔・密史纳
美国宇航局  喷气推进实验所
如果大气中存在许多甲烷
So if you had a lot of methane in the atmosphere
那么很可能会产生较高的温度
you'd had likely very warm temperatures.
但24亿年前  一群新生的水生微生物
But 2.4 billion years ago, a new group of underwater microbes
开始从阳光中吸收能量
began absorbing energy from the Sun
这一过程被称为光合作用
in a process called photosynthesis.
通过将二氧化碳和水转化为能量
By converting carbon dioxide and water into energy,
光合作用形成的新的有毒废物开始污染地球
photosynthesis polluted the Earth with a toxic new waste product,
氧气
oxygen.
大量的氧气
Vast amounts of it.
在24亿年之前  氧气是毒气
Prior to 2.4 billion years ago, oxygen was a poison
任何地球上的生命都不需要氧气
and any life that was on Earth did not use oxygen,
氧气被认为是废气
it was considered a waste gas.
所有不喜氧气的生命
All of that life that didn't like oxygen
被暴露在富氧环境中
was exposed to this rich oxygen environment
情况开始变得很紧迫
and it caused great deal of stress.
甲烷生物快乐的生活在无氧世界中
Methane creatures were happy to live in this oxygen free world.
这时氧气出现了
Now, when oxygen finally does appear,
这是它们历史中最不幸的灾难
it was like the worst calamity in their history.
当氧气席卷全球时
As oxygen flooded the world,
甲烷被氧化
it oxidized methane
成为二氧化碳
turning it into carbon dioxide.
以甲烷为生的生物快速灭绝
The methane consuming creatures died off in a fast extinction event,
这被称为"大氧化事件"
called the great oxygen catastrophe.
由于地球失去了起保暖作用的甲烷
And as Earth lost its warming blanket of methane gas
整个星球开始冻结
the planet froze over.
如果是生产氧气的生命是
But if oxygen producing life, was the primary trigger
首次"雪地球"形成的主要诱因
of the first Snowball Earth,
这些生命现在需要则寻找到温暖的地方
that life now needed to find a warm place
来躲避由它们引起的灾难
to escape the disaster it had caused.
那时的地球比起现在  构造过程更活跃
The Earth at that time was even more energetic tectonically than it is now.
地球的形成会产生巨大的热量
The formation of the Earth produced enormous heat,
这些热量会来到地表  过程很慢
that heat comes to the surface, it's slowing,
但那时有许多火山  每个火山周围
but back then many more volcanoes, around every volcano
都会出现这样一个被融化的湖泊状地区
would have been this melted lake-like zone
生命就在这里蓬勃发展
where life could have thrived.
要演示火山活动如何为生命提供保温所
To show how volcanism could have carved out cozy niches for life
你只需要一把喷枪和一个大冰球
all you need is a blow torch and a big ball of ice.
我们在"冰雕店"
We are here at Carving Ice,
这是罗兰・赫尔南德斯所有的冰雕室
an ice house owned by Roland Hernandez,
他是一位出色地冰雕家  他为我们制作了
an amazing ice sculptor who has created for us
这个全冰的半球  代表"雪地球"
this hemisphere of solid ice which represents Snowball Earth.
我们把它放在这个推车上
We've placed it up here on this dolly
以便能用工业喷枪  从下面加热
so that we can heat it from below with an industrial blow torch
用来演示在雪地球时期地下火山活动
to represent the type of heating that we would experience on Snowball Earth,
所带来的热量
from vulcanism deep beneath the surface.
现在我打开它
Now let me light this up.
-给你喷枪  -好的
- All right, passing you the torch. - Okay.
科学家们怀疑  由地表下的火山活动
Scientists suspect that the extreme heat pressure
所产生的极大的热量和压力
generated by volcanism beneath the Earth's surface
可能会使冰层开裂  从而为生命提供避难所
would have created cracks in the ice for life to take refuge.
你能看到这些裂缝是如何贯穿整个冰块
Okay, so you can see how the cracks are formed all throughout the ice,
沿着顶端这里...
along the top here...
这同"雪地球"事件中出现的
These are very similar to the types of cracks
裂缝是非常相似的
that would form during a Snowball Earth event.
在这些裂缝中你就可以得到
It's in these cracks where you can get the mixture
一些液体  一些热量
of a little bit of liquid, a little bit of heat,
和一些化学物质的混合体
a little bit of chemistry,
换句话说  这是生命生根发芽
in other words, the perfect ingredients for generating
甚至蓬勃发展所需环境的完美组合
an environment where life can take root and even thrive.
火山活动并非只是生命
Volcanism wasn't just key
在雪地球时期生存的关键
to life survival during Snowball Earth.
它也许最终迫使了冰川的消退
It also may have forced the glaciers to finally retreat.
所有这些从火山口冒出的气体
See, all these gases that are coming out of the volcanoes,
例如水蒸气  二氧化碳  二氧化硫
things like water vapor, carbon dioxide, sulfur dioxide
它们都进入了大气之中
for example, which are escaping into the atmosphere
经过千万年的时间
and over time, over tens of millions of years,
它们不断地提高温室气体的水平
you're building up these levels of greenhouse gasses.
在某一时刻  大气变得足够温暖
At some point, it's going to get so warm in the atmosphere
冰川开始融化
that the ice begins to melt.
"雪地球"的两个时期
Both episodes of Snowball Earth,
首先是24亿年前
the first 2.4 billion years ago,
其次是6亿年前
and the second, 600 million years ago,
都对早期的生命产生了巨大的影响
placed profound stresses on early life.
但奇怪的是  两个时期后都有大量物种出现
But oddly, both were followed by enormous flowerings of new species.
通过沉积的地质记录
We know from the sedimentary record,
就在动物开始出现并繁荣前
that just before animals bloomed into existence,
大量的磷进入了海洋中
an enormous amount of phosphorous came in to the ocean,
大块的含磷岩石
there were big rocks of phosphorous
被腐蚀了  从而使得海洋中磷的含量上升
they eroded as that erosion occurred phosphorous levels in the ocean rose.
突然间生命开始繁荣发展了
All of a sudden life is able to just bloom.
这可能真正导致了两个时期的生命多样化
This may really have caused the diversification two times,
先是23亿年前微生物世界的多样化
of the microbial world, at 2.3 billion years ago,
更重要的是  对我们来说
but more importantly to us,
它可能很好地促进了6亿年前
it really probably helped the diversification of the animals
动物的多样化
that 600 million years ago.
虽然"雪地球"带来了地球上最严酷的气候
Although Snowball Earth produced some the planet's harshest weather,
生命不仅存活了下来
life not only managed to survive,
而且比以往更坚强的繁荣发展
it bounced back stronger than ever,
因此这次灾难只能在
which is why this disaster only ranks as number 5
灾难时刻中位列第五
on our list of worst days.
我们继续倒数
But as the countdown continues,
确凿的证据浮出水面
forensic evidence is finally emerging,
它将可能解释一场更极端的灾难
that just may explain a far deadlier cataclysm...
一次杀戮盛宴
A mass killing spree
恐怕可以说是地球上最古老的谋杀案了
that stands as the oldest murder mystery on the planet.
在我们倒数地球七大灾难时刻的时候
So far, on our countdown of the 7 worst days on Earth
我们看到地球曾在月球形成撞击中破损不堪
we've seen our planet battered, during the Moon forming impact,
被晚期重度轰炸洗礼
baptized by the Late Heavy Bombardment
被"雪地球"几乎完全冻住
and almost completely frozen over by Snowball Earth.
现在我们将再前进一亿年
Now we travel forward over a 100 million years,
地球经历了其历史上最大规模的屠杀之一
as the world is rocked by one of the greatest mass killings in its history.
第四位
Number four on our list.
奥陶纪大灭绝
The ordovician extinction.
在地球上数十亿年生命的历史中
In the billions of years of life on Earth,
99%曾出现过的物种最终都消亡了
99% of all species that ever lived have ultimately vanished.
大部分是由于五次大规模灭绝事件
Mostly due to five mass extinction events.
第一个便是奥陶纪时期
The first was during the ordovician period,
4.5亿年前
450 million years ago.
奥陶纪大规模灭绝是
The mass extinction during the ordovician is
唐・布朗李
华盛顿大学
在五大灭绝事件中最为神秘莫测
the most mysterious of the so called big five
主要由于它发生的年代最为久远
simply because it was the one that was the oldest.
而其余四个事件的发生时间据今越来越近
Everyone after that was closer to us in time
相隔时间越久远
and the further back in time you go
历史原貌对我们来说就越模糊
the more fuzzy our scientific view of the past is.
奥陶纪时期
During the Ordovician period,
地球上有三大洋和四大陆
the globe was covered with three major oceans, and four super continents.
陆地尚且贫瘠
The land was still bare,
海洋已遍布生物
but the oceans teamed with life,
包括艳丽的珊瑚
including brilliant corals
和地球最早的鱼类
and the planet's first fish.
然而一场突发的灾难横扫海洋
Then a mysterious cataclysm swept the seas,
地球上60%的生物
and 60% of life on Earth
灰飞烟灭
vanished.
有一系列的可能性解释
There's a couple of possibilities.
首先是地球再次变冷  原因何在
Number one, it got cold again, so why would it have gotten cold?
有可能是板块构造运动
Well, it could have been the plate tectonics
使得原本温暖的大陆南移至两级地区
moved all of the formerly warm continents down to the polar regions
导致整体性的降温
and that dropped the temperature of everything.
多年来  科学家将奥陶纪大灭绝
For years, the scientists blamed the Ordovician extinction
归咎于毁灭性的冰河时期
on a devastating ice age.
但现在一些研究者提出
But now some researchers propose
罪魁祸首可能来自宇宙
that the mass killer could have been something from the cosmos.
例如伽马射线爆发
Like a gamma ray burst,
宇宙最强的爆发
the biggest blast in the universe.
伽马射线大爆发是由于
A gamma ray burst is a colossal explosion of a star
恒星不对称爆炸产生的
that occurs asymmetrically
两束方向相反的直线光束
there are two oppositely directed beams,
亚历克・菲力彭科
加州大学伯克利分校
充满高能速的粒子流和辐射
of very energetic, high speed particles and radiation,
像激光一样急速穿越宇宙空间
they go zipping through space, kind of like a laser beam.
如果光束接落到地球上
If that beam is aimed right at Earth
便会造成巨大的破坏
it can cause significant damage here.
一场大爆发将会蒸发掉
A large burst would vaporize
地球上三分之一的臭氧保护层
1/3 of the planet protective ozone layer.
地球遭受重创面的生物
And creatures on the side of the Earth facing the onslaught
它们将直接暴露在致命的宇宙辐射下
would suffer lethal radiation exposure.
我们可以在地球上演示
The destructive energy of a gamma ray burst
伽马射线大爆发的破坏力量
can be demonstrated here on Earth.
这是地球仪  代表奥陶纪末期的地球
Here's our globe, representing the Earth at the end of the ordovician period,
一部分科学家认为当时的大灭绝
a time where one group of scientists thinks
可能是伽马射线大爆发造成的
that a gamma ray burst may have triggered a mass extinction.
外面包裹的纸代表臭氧层
The paper represents the ozone layer
这把丙烷火枪模拟伽马射线爆发
and the gamma ray burst is represented by this propane torch.
8  9  10秒  仅仅这段时间
8, 9, 10 seconds were, that is all they say it would take
地球三分之一的臭氧层将被破坏
to destroy about 1/3 of the Earth's ozone.
当然伽马射线大爆发没让地球烧焦
So of course the gamma ray burst didn't actually torch the Earth
但当它到达地球时确实摧毁了臭氧层
but it did destroy the ozone that it encountered
其破坏了地球这一侧的
that would have messed with the chemistry of the ozone molecules
臭氧分子
on this side of the globe.
臭氧层遭到破坏后
And when the ozone was destroyed
劳拉・丹莉
格里菲斯天文台
紫外线就能直达地表
UV radiation can penetrate into the surface
紫外线辐射对生物是致命的
and the ultraviolet radiation is very lethal to life.
它能破坏DNA
It's very destructive to DNA.
因此伽马射线爆发对臭氧层的破坏
So, it may be that a gamma ray burst destroying the ozone layer
有可能促使甚至导致了
contributed or maybe even triggered
奥陶纪末期的大灭绝
a mass extinction at the end of the Ordovician.
削弱臭氧层的同时
In addition to depleting the ozone layer
伽马射线大爆发会破坏
a large gamma ray burst also could have ripped apart
大气层中氮气和氧气的分子结构
nitrogen and oxygen molecules in the atmosphere
生成二氧化氮  进而形成烟雾层
producing a gaseous smog of nitrogen dioxide
阻挡阳光射入  造成第二次劫难
that blocked sunlight and sent off a secondary disaster.
冰河时期
An ice age.
伽马射线爆发是否是诱因目前尚不明确
It's not clear whether that could have been caused by a gamma ray burst.
但至少奥陶纪的大灭绝
But at least part of the Ordovician extinction
有一个特征
seems to have been marked
即大量生活在地表的生物灭绝了
by a huge decrease in the number of surface dwelling creatures,
例如生活在陆地表面
like on the Earth's surface
或者是海洋浅水层的生物
or in the surface layers of the ocean.
这或许能够说明是紫外线辐射
That may well indicate that it was ultraviolet radiation
而非其他因素导致了生物死亡
that killed them off rather than some other factor.
伽马射线大爆发也许是
A gamma ray burst could be one explanation
地球第一次大灭绝的原因之一
for the first mass annihilation of life on Earth.
但一个惊人的新设想
But a startling new hypothesis
指向了另一种宇宙能量
points to a different cosmic force.
奇异而致命的弓形激波
A bizarre and potentially deadly phenomenon known as a bow shock.
弓形激波是运动物体前方的物质
A bow shock forms when there's compression
受到挤压时形成的
of material in front of a moving object.
举个例子  行驶在水中的船
So for example if you have a boat swimming along,
通过压迫正前方的水而形成波浪
it creates a wave a compression in front of it,
但随着船的前行水波便逐渐弯曲了
but then bends around as the boat moves through.
我们所在的星系在宇宙中快速运动
Well, our galaxy is moving rapidly through space.
因此它会挤压前方星系间的气体
So it can compress intergalactic gas in front of it
导致其升温并产生辐射
heating it up creating cosmic rays
部分辐射可能到达地球上
and some of those cosmic rays can then hit the Earth.
太阳系在银河系中来回运动
Our Solar System oscillates through the Milky Way
每6400万年在银河系主圆盘中
traveling above and below the main disc of the galaxy
上下运动一次
every 64 million years.
一旦脱离星系的保护性磁场
Once outside the galaxy protective magnetic field,
我们的地球便毫无保护的暴露在
our planet is vulnerable to deadly cosmic rays
星系弓形激波产生的致命宇宙射线中了
generated by the galactic bow shock.
这跟湖上的滑水者相似
Much like a wakeboarder on a lake.
滑水运动很好地解释了弓形激波的原理
Wakeboarding would be a reasonable example of bow shock in space.
迈克尔・密史纳
美国宇航局  喷气推进实验所
当滑水者处于快艇弓形波的范围内
While the wakeboarder is well within the confines of the bow wave of the boat
水面平稳  易于滑行
the water is very calm and smooth
站到板上很轻松
and he has no trouble standing up.
但当他滑出波浪的边缘时
But during those periods where he moves out of the edge of the wave
水面开始无序地波动
the water becomes a bit more turbulent and a bit more chaotic
他要站住就有些难了
and he has trouble standing up.
在宇宙空间里也是一样
The same thing is true in space,
大多数时间
for most of the time,
太阳和地球都在银河系磁场的
the Earth and Sun are well within the protective confines
保护范围内
of the Milky Way galaxy's magnetic field
使它们不受弓形激波产生的
protecting it from the cosmic rays and other
宇宙射线或其他辐射影响
radiation that's coming in from the bow shock.
但当太阳和地球
But during those periods when the Earth and the Sun
飞出这艘"星系飞船"的顶端
rise above the galactic plane
就更容易受到其产生的宇宙射线的影响
is much vulnerable to all of these cosmic rays coming from the bow shock.
化石记录显示每隔6200万年
Fossil records indicate that the biodiversity of many species
大量物种的多样性增加和减少一次
may increase and decrease in 62 million years cycles.
该循环与地球每6400万年就会
Those cycles closely coinciding with the times of greatest
暴露于弓形激波宇宙射线下的时间
exposure to cosmic rays from the galactic bow shock
非常相近
which occur every 64 million years.
二者之间是否有一定联系
Could the two events be connected?
两次大灭绝恰好都发生在
Two of the mass extinctions happened to have occurred
太阳位于我们银河系最高端
at about the time when the sun was highest above the plane of our galaxy.
这意味着那个特殊的位置
That suggests that there is something about that particular location
其特殊之处导致了那些大灭绝
that's special, causing these mass extinctions.
奥陶纪大灭绝期间
During the Ordovician extinction,
地球可能因足量的星系弓形激波
Earth could have been blasted with enough deadly radiation
所产生的致命辐射
from the galactic bow shock
导致各种基因突变和DNA损害
to unleash genetic mutations and DNA damage
使得近半数物种灭绝
that wiped out over half of all species.
这个想法未经证实
This is not yet a well tested idea,
只是一个设想
it is just out there on the drawing board
但它可以解释地球大灭绝的
but it could explain some of the possible periodicity
一些可能性的周期性
in Earth's mass extinctions.
但当奥陶纪绝大部分物种都灭绝的时候
But while the Ordovician extinction was fatal to most species
有些物种抓住了机会
some grasped at the opportunity.
就像在花园里除草
It's like pulling weeds out of a garden,
你清扫  清除  花草变得稀疏
you sort of clean out and weed out and thin out.
奥陶纪的大灭绝似乎就是如此
That seems to have happened in the Ordovician mass extinctions.
物种此消彼长
Some creatures which died out allowed others to diversify.
奥陶纪是第一次大灭绝
The Ordovician was the first mass extinction
但不是最惨烈的
but hardly the worst.
地球第三大灾难时刻
Number three on our countdown of the worst days on Earth.
是最著名的史前灭绝
It's the most famous die off in pre-history.
但是如果你自认了解龙灭绝的原因
But if you think you know what killed the dinosaurs
你也许会大吃一惊
you may be in for a surprise
而现在  有些科学家认为
because some scientists now argue that
恐龙灭绝缘于一颗巨型陨石撞击的普遍说法
the common explanation of a single giant impact on a single disastrous day
可能是错误的
is itself about to be blasted away.
我们倒数的地球灾难时刻中
In our countdown to the very worst day on Earth,
没有哪次灾难的主题
no catastrophe has been the subject of
比大撞击最终为人类发展开道
more public fascination and sensational headlines
更能吸引大众且引起轰动了
than the bombardment that ultimately cleared the path for mankind.
但今天  争议性的新假设挑战
But today controversial new hypothesis challenge the concept
一次灾难性的撞击使恐龙灭绝的观点
that a single disastrous impact wiped out the dinosaurs
便是  地球第三大灾难时刻
and led to the third worst day on Earth.
白垩纪-第三纪灭绝
The KT extinction.
六千五百万年前
65 million years ago
我们有类似于非洲的世界
we would have seen a world something like Africa,
因为动物数量众多
in terms of the numbers of animals out there.
但是没有哺乳动物  只有大恐龙
But instead of being mammals, we had big dinosaurs
彼得・沃德
华盛顿大学教授
大量的三角龙  成群的梁龙
herds of triceratops, herds of diplo dinosaurs,
大小不一的食肉恐龙  最大的是霸王龙
small to big predators, the largest being T-Rex.
恐龙在史前世界称霸了约2亿年
Dinosaurs ruled the pre-historic world for almost 200 million years,
之后某物灭绝了地球上三分之二的生物
then something took out 2/3 of all living creatures
包括巨型野兽[恐龙]
including the giant beasts.
研究多年以后  绝大部分专家认为
After years of searching for clues, most experts now agree
一次大灾难终结了恐龙
that a single cataclysm doomed the dinosaurs.
6500万年前一颗直径9.6公里的小行星撞击地球
The evidence for an impact of a 6-mile wide asteroid 65 million years ago,
丹・杜尔达
西南研究所
科学上已经很好的证明了这一点
is about as good as anything gets in science.
六千五百万年前
65 million years ago,
一块珠穆朗玛峰体积的岩石
a rock the size of Mount Everest
破空而落
barreled down from the sky
撞入尤卡坦半岛
and slammed into the Yucatan peninsula
位于现在的墨西哥希克苏鲁伯附近
near modern Chicxulub, Mexico.
此次撞击引发了一条毁灭链
The impact unleashed an unstoppable chain of destruction.
从该地区开始  然后横扫全球
First locally, and then across the globe.
第三纪灭绝是由小行星撞击引起的
The KT is an asteroid driving to an extinction
当其撞击地球时
when a big rock from the space came down
小部分恐龙直接死亡
clunked a few dinosaurs on the head.
但是毁灭机制却是这件事的副效应
But the kill mechanism was really the secondary effects of this.
它导致大气层变黑
It would have been darkened the atmosphere
酸雨  整个生物圈改变
acid rain, a change in the entire biosphere.
但是单一碰撞学说的反对者
But opponents of the single impact theory,
举出一组令人信服的证据
point to a convincing array of evidence,
包括第三纪灭绝事件地质层或死亡层中
including high levels of the asteroid element iridium
具有高含量的小行星元素铱
at the KT event's geological boundary or death layer.
当然这个确凿的证据本身
And of course the smoking gun itself,
就是现代墨西哥的水下火山口
the underwater crater in modern Mexico.
但是旧案得以了结吗
But is this cold case finally closed?
一些科学家现在认为
Some scientists now argue that the
尤卡坦半岛的小行星有共犯
Yucatan asteroid had accomplices.
似乎很多原因都可能触发这次事件
There's seems to be various causes that could trigger this.
有时候  几个原因同时出现
In some cases, several causes come together
格雷格・鲁克林
加州大学圣塔克鲁兹分校
造成很糟糕的情况
and sort of confluence of bad circumstances
导致了具有特殊破坏性的灭绝事件
to provide a particularly damaging extinction event.
第三纪毁灭之前的数百万年
Millions of years before the KT extinction
已经有巨大的熔岩流注入德干岩群
vast lava flows had been pouring out into the Deccan traps,
那是现在位于印度西南的系列熔岩层
a series of lava beds, now located in southwest India.
这些溢流玄武岩曾喷出的岩浆
These flood basalts once spewed out enough magma
能覆盖1600万平方公里
to cover over a million square miles,
并喷出一种有毒的气体
and belched up a toxic brew of gases
也许改变了整个地球的气候
that could have altered the climate around the world.
火山爆发的时间
That period of eruption is pretty coincident
与六千五百万年前的灭绝也很符合
with the extinction 65 million years ago, as well.
实际上  在第三纪撞击和大灭绝之前
In fact, they were going on millions of years
这种情况已经持续了几百万年
before the KT impact and before the extinctions.
所以  原因也许是一个复合因素
And, so, perhaps can be a complicating factor.
在这个假设里  恐龙被双重淘汰
In this scenario, the dinosaurs received a double knockout blow.
首先是德干岩群的活跃的火山活动
First the rapid volcanism of the Deccan traps,
然后是尤卡坦半岛撞击
then the Yucatan impact.
一小群反对者甚至宣称
And a small group of dissenters goes even further,
在六千五百万年前的几乎同一时间
claiming that multiple asteroids stroke Earth
有多次小行星撞击地球
at roughly the same time 65 million years ago.
他们认为  尤卡坦半岛撞击不算最剧烈
According to them, the Yucatan impact wasn't the largest,
只是人类对其记录很完整
only the best documented.
有些人认为可能有多次撞击
Some people think that there may be have been multiple impacts,
亚历克・菲力彭科
加州大学伯克利分校
陨石雨般的撞击
a shower of impacts, for example.
也许他们来自同一物体  它碎成数块
Perhaps they came from a single object that broke apart.
这种假设的支持者
Supporters of this hypothesis
指出了一种可疑的地质特征
point to a suspicious geologic feature,
印度海岸处有块直径595公里的盆地
a 370-mile basin off the coast of India.
比尤卡坦半岛撞击点面积大三倍多
More than 3 times larger than the Yucatan impact site.
但对于这个所谓的湿婆陨石坑  争论不断
But controversy swirls around this so called Shiva crater,
它以印度教毁灭神的名字命名
named after the Hindu god of destruction,
讨论包括它到底是不是个火山口
including whether it is even a crater at all.
虽然它的外型像个环状的大坑
While this feature certainly looks circular and looks crater-like
但是没有其他证据证明它的确是撞击所致
there is no other evidence that it's an actual impact structure.
虽然恐龙灭绝争论不一
For some the dinosaur die-off debate rages on.
但是大部分科学家都认为
But most scientists agree
这次毁灭事件对于小型哺乳动物来说
the apocalyptic event was a very fortunate day
却是很幸运的
for small mammals,
它们再也不必成为霸王龙的盘中餐了
that were no longer dinner for T-Rex.
如果没有第三纪大撞击和火山作用
Had it not been for the KT impact and the volcanism
劳拉・丹莉
格里菲斯天文台
也就是恐龙灭绝的时候
that was also at the time of the extinction of the dinosaurs,
也许哺乳动物就不可能崛起
the mammals probably wouldn't have reason to the prominence that they did
由于哺乳动物的崛起
and thank heaven for the rise of mammals
人类得以起源
because that led to the rise of humans.
第三纪灭绝引发了一个严峻的问题
A KT extinction raises a sobering question...
是否有一天人类也会跟恐龙的下场一样
Could humans one day go the way of the dinosaurs?
这是来自密歇根艾德里安市的汤姆・莫尔想要
That's what viewer Tom Moore from Adrian, Michigan wanted to
询问宇宙的问题
ask The Universe.
地球会再次与一颗第三纪时期大小的小行星相撞吗
-汤姆・莫尔  密歇根  艾德里安市
汤姆  地球绝对可能会遭受
Well, Tom, Earth could definitely be hit
另一颗第三纪时期大小的彗星或小行星的撞击
by another KT-sized comet or asteroid.
它们就在那
They're out there.
好消息是我们正追踪大部分大行星的位置
The good news is we are tracking the position of most of the big ones.
如果我们发现一颗可能撞向地球
So if we ever find one with Earth's name written on it
希望能在它撞击地球前将其打偏
hopefully we'll be able to deflect it before it reaches Earth.
白垩纪-第三纪灭绝事件终结了霸王龙
The KT event toppled T-Rex,
但这只能算作是
but it only ranks as number three
第三大地球灾难时刻
on our countdown of worst days on Earth.
排名第二的是最惨烈的灭绝
Number two was the mother of all extinctions,
地球生物所经历的最惨烈的毁灭事件
the greatest die-off that life on Earth has ever suffered.
这仍是科学领域最大的未解之谜之一
It is also been one of the biggest unsolved mysteries in science,
直到现在
until now.
随着灾难倒数的高潮临近
As we near the climax of our countdown
我们重新开启最古老的未解悬案
we reopen one of the oldest cold cases,
这个未解谋杀之谜发生在2亿5千万年前
an unsolved murder mystery that happened 250 million years ago,
大约在恐龙灭绝两亿年前
almost 200 million years before the downfall of the dinosaurs.
第二大灾难时刻
The second worst day
见证了地球史上规模最大的物种灭绝
witness the greatest mass extinction in the planet's history.
大灭绝
一次被称为大灭绝的灾难
A cataclysm known as the great dying.
二叠纪期间  地球上充满了
During the Permian period, Earth was a wondrous world
类哺乳的爬行动物和奇异的海洋生物
of mammal-like reptiles and exotic sea creatures.
之后  95%的生物从这颗星球上消失
Then, 90% of all life disappeared from the planet.
这是地球上命运多舛的几万年
This is a bad few hundred thousand years on planet Earth,
但确是最具灾难性的
but it was certainly the most catastrophic.
彼得・沃德
华盛顿大学教授
此次生物灭绝数量之多  可能空前绝后
More life died then, than any time since and maybe any time before.
也是规模最大  死亡最惨重的一次
This was the biggest and the baddest of them all.
几十年来  科学家们搜寻线索
For decades, scientists have sifted through clues,
试图揭开大灭绝的谜团
struggling to solve the mystery of the great dying,
那时的生物真是命悬一线啊
when the survival of life itself seemed to hang by a thread.
其中可能性最大的是
One of the prime suspects
一座超级火山冲破西伯利亚  地裂数百公里
a super volcano that tore Siberia open for hundreds of miles
喷发了至少一百万年
erupted for at least a million years
产生了史上最大规模的熔岩流
and produced the greatest lava flows ever known,
足以将整个美国埋在数百米深的熔岩流下
enough to bury the entire United States, thousands of feet deep.
这不只是座巨型火山
This wasn't a single giant volcano,
简直就是地表开裂
it was simply cracks in the Earth
喷射熔岩一样
and they were like pumping out lava.
那就像是消防水龙头  岩浆喷涌到处都是
It's like a fire hose, spewing lava everywhere.
熔岩所经之处  必将生灵涂炭
Well that sort of would have killed anything in its way.
人们相信这些煤层
It's believed that you have these beds of coal
就在现在的西伯利亚
on what it is now Siberia,
熔岩在煤层之下喷发
which then had lava erupting underneath them
将煤燃烧并产生有害的温室气体
and burning the coal and putting sorts of noxious
格雷格・鲁克林
加州大学圣塔克鲁兹分校
和其他有毒气体进入大气中
greenhouse and other toxic gasses into the atmosphere
对生物圈的影响非常可怕
and really putting strong stress on to the biosphere.
与日俱增的全球变暖给多数动物带来灾难
The increased global warming was fatal to most animals.
但植物通常靠二氧化碳生长
But plants usually thrived on carbon dioxide,
那么为何它们也经历了史无前例的灭绝呢
so why did they also succumb at rates that have never been equal?
我们认为的  也是刚发现的
There's a second killer in the story
这次事件的二号杀手
that we think and just now discovering,
是地球上第一次出现的
and that's the presence for the first time on the planet
大量硫酸氢气体
of massive amounts of hydrogen sulphate gas.
同坏鸡蛋所散发的气体一样  绝对的毒气
The same stuff you see with rotten eggs, that is a true poison
我觉得  它与热结合
and yet with the heat combined I think
造成了规模最大的生物灭绝
it caused this greatest of mass extinctions.
如果科学陪审团仍然在为
If the scientific jury is still debating the cause
三叠纪灭绝的原因辩论
of the Permian-Triassic extinction,
他们一致认为那段时间是到目前为止
no one disputes that those were the darkest days
地球上最黑暗的日子
for life on our planet so far.
但地球上的生命不能  也不会幸免于
But life on Earth cannot and will not survive an event
一次科学家预测的如死亡一样必然的事件
that scientists predict it's as unavoidable as death itself.
地球第一大灾难时刻
The number one worst day on planet Earth.
末日审判
The solar apocalypse.
再过50亿年  太阳将走到生命的尽头
In five billion years, our Sun will reach the end of its life,
随着核燃料的耗尽
as it exhausts its nuclear fuel,
它将经受一次毁灭性的转变
it will undergo a disastrous transformation
膨胀成一颗巨型恒星
bloating into a red giant star
是现在体积的二百倍
200 times its original size.
其膨胀过程中  它将首先吞掉水星
As it swells, it will first engulf Mercury,
之后是金星
then Venus,
被烧烬的地球也将被推上更远轨道
the incinerated Earth will either be pushed to a higher orbit
或是被吞没
or swallowed itself.
好消息是  太阳烧烬地球的那一天
The goods news, humans won't be around
人类早已不在此生活了
the day our Sun incinerates Earth.
但在这之前  我们将长期被烈日烘烤
Bad news, we will have been roasted long before.
太阳逐渐变亮  大约每十亿年增加百分之十
The Sun gets brighter, about 10% every billion years
因此  不到十亿年
and so in less than a billion years,
太阳将变得足够明亮
the Sun will be bright enough.
据估计  这会抽走大气中的几乎所有
It's predicted that it will pump basically all
或是大部分的二氧化碳
or most of the carbon dioxide out of the atmosphere,
那些依赖二氧化碳生存的生物  如植物
and so things that rely on carbon dioxide like plants
将很难在自然界中生存
are gonna have a hard time surviving in a natural world.
随着星球枯萎和海洋蒸发
As plants shrivel and oceans evaporate
生物学家预测未来将有一次超级大灭绝
biologists predict a future mega-mass extinction.
动物时代将在五亿年内结束
The age of animals will end in about 500 million years.
我们在未来有足够的时间像动物一样生存
We have as much time in the future to be alive as an animal
就像过去一样  我们已经成功一半了
as we had in the past, we're half way through,
这是个好消息
that's a sobering thought.
我们目睹了地球经历了形成月球的撞击
We've seen Earth smacked by the giant Moon forming impact,
在晚期大轰炸时期  被狂轰乱炸  横扫一空
strafed and sterilized during the Late Heavy Bombardment
以及冰冻成一个巨大的雪地球
and frozen into a giant snowball,
在第一次大规模灭绝期间
a cosmic force ravished an ancient water world
宇宙能量灭绝了古海底世界
during the first mass extinction,
大灭绝期间  一次近似全体消亡紧跟其后
followed by a near total extinction during the Great Dying
还有恐龙时代的惊人落幕
and the spectacular fall of the dinosaurs.
在地球最终被太阳炙烤之前
What else lies in store
还会发生什么呢
before our planet is ultimately baked by the Sun...?
地球在死亡前
Earth will certainly continue to experience
必定会继续经历灾难
disasters all the way up until the very end
直至太阳的红巨星阶段为地球画上句号
and sun's red giant phase brings ends to the story.
历史证明地球是一颗不可预知的星球
History has proven that Earth is an unpredictable planet
环绕在一个非常危险的银河地带
orbiting in a very dangerous galactic neighbourhood.
为了生存  人类必须从过往灾难中学习
To survive, mankind must learn from the worst days of our past
试着在未知的宇宙事件发生前做好准备
and try to prepare for whatever the cosmos might throw at us,
只有增加对宇宙的认识
only by increasing our knowledge of the universe,
我们才可能繁荣发展并好好享受
and we hope to thrive and fully enjoy
地球上最后的五亿年
our final 500 million years of life on Earth.